Finding Aid for the Norris Hundley Papers LSC.0577
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 3: The Great Thirst and other publications, circa 1808-2009
  - Subseries 3C: Research files, circa 1808-2009
    - MWD of Southern California: Water information and numbers, 1993-1998 (Box 89, Folder 14)
    - Exhibit A, undated; (1 item). (Box 68, Folder 4)
      Base contract price.
    - Exhibit B, undated; (1 item). (Box 68, Folder 5)
      Shortage sharing.
    - Exhibit C, undated; (1 item). (Box 68, Folder 6)
      Shortage sharing procedures.
    - Exhibit D, undated; (1 item). (Box 68, Folder 7)
      Shortage premium.
    - Exhibit E, undated; (1 item). (Box 68, Folder 8)
      Price redetermination.
    - Exhibit F, undated; (1 item). (Box 68, Folder 9)
      Transfers of additional available water.
    - Exhibit G, undated; (1 item). (Box 68, Folder 10)
      Term right of first refusal.
    - Exhibit H, undated; (1 item). (Box 68, Folder 11)
      Calculations Determining Whether IID Environmental Migration Expenditures Exceed Limits.
    - Millerton Lake, 1997 October; (1 item). (Box 68, Folder 12)
      Facility Descriptions and Updated Cost Estimates for Millerton Lake Enlargement.
    - Missions--Irrigation, 1934-1974; (11 items). (Box 68, Folder 13)
      Copies of papers and documents from the Santa Barbara Mission archives re early mission irrigation systems. Includes Santa Barbara, San Diego, and San Fernando Rey.
    - Oral histories, 1995 April 14 (Box 90, Folder 1)
    - Owens Valley Monitor, 1997-1998; (1 item). (Box 68, Folder 14)
      Inyo County Water Department's Annual Report on Activities and Conditions in the Owen's Valley.
    - Pacific Institute for Study in Development, Environment, and Security, 1996-1998; (4 items). (Box 68, Folder 15)
      Working papers:
      "California Water Transfers: An Evaluation of the Economic Framework and a Spatial Analysis of the Potential Impacts" (1998).
      "The Economic Underpinnings of Efforts to Create Water Markets in California: Why the Well is Still Dry" (1996).
    - R.A. Brian and agriculture figures, circa 1985 (Box 90, Folder 2)
    - Reisner, Marc, 1997; (1 item). (Box 69, Folder 1)
      Water Policy and Farmland Protection: A New Approach (Washington, D.C.: American Farmland Trust).
    - Rubin, Hal, 1989 February 10; (1 item). (Box 69, Folder 2)
      Article: "Combat zone."
    - Santa Barbara Mission archives, circa 1808-1820; (17 items). (Box 69, Folder 3)
      Photocopied and transcribed Spanish letters regarding el Pueblo de Los Angeles.
    - St. Francis Dam testimony and court transcripts, 1928 March 21 (Box 91, Folder 1-4)
      This box includes copies of the original court transcripts from the inquest into the St. Francis Dam disaster, including the coroner's testimony. The original transcripts are held at the Henry E. Huntington Library.
    - St. Francis Dam site photographs and negatives, undated (Box 90, Folder 3)
    - Southern California Watershed Corporation, 1995; (1 item). (Box 69, Folder 4)
      Proceedings of the Southern California Watershed Conference: Making watersheds work (Santa Monica: Heal the Bay, 1995).
    - State of Arizona vs. State of California, 1960 June 10; (1 item). (Box 69, Folder 5)
      Comments, suggestions, and motions of the California defendants re the special master's draft report.
    - Storey, Brit Allan, 1995 August 5; (1 item). (Box 69, Folder 6)
      Draft paper: "Modern Quandaries for the Bureau of Reclamation."
    - Storper, Michael, circa 1986; (1 item). (Box 69, Folder 7)
      Essay: "Subsidies in the State of Water Project: A Reply to the MWD" (in response to Warren Abbott).
    - Transboundary water issues, 1989, 2006 (Box 90, Folder 4)
    - Tribal water rights: Navajo, 2003-2006 (Box 90, Folder 5)
    - Tribal water rights: Pollack materials, 2005-2007 (Box 90, Folder 6)
    - Vernon Irrigation Company vs. City of Los Angeles, et al, 1893; (1 item). (Box 69, Folder 8)
      Transcript on appeal re ownership, usage, and rights of a tract of land and water usage and rights of Los Angeles River.
    - Vernon Irrigation Company vs. City of Los Angeles, et al, 1893-1894; (4 items). (Box 69, Folder 9)
      Closing brief.
    - Water Conservation in California, 1976 May; (1 item). (Box 69, Folder 10)
      Bulletin no.198 of the Department of Water Resources.
    - Water Education Foundation, 1997 May; (1 item). (Box 69, Folder 11)
      Colorado River Compact Symposium.
    - Water Reporter, 1991-1998; 19 items). (Box 69, Folder 12)
      Inyo County Water Department newsletter.
    - Water Resource Center Archives, 1968, 1994; (5 items). (Box 69, Folder 13)
      Contains photocopied material regarding concerns over flood losses, a photocopy of The Water Encyclopedia, and a copy of Municipal Water Conservation.
    - Water and the West: epilogue draft, undated (Box 90, Folder 7)
    - Water and the West: Stanley Pollack documents, 2007-2009 (Box 90, Folder 8)
    - Water and the West: revisions, circa 2004 (Box 90, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 3D: Reviews, 1966-2002
    The series includes correspondence and clippings related to reviews of Hundley's various publications.
    - Amerasia Journal, 1975-1977 (Box 90, Folder 12)
    - El-Ashry, 1989 September-October (Box 90, Folder 13)
    - Dividing the Waters, 1966-1967 (Box 90, Folder 14)
    - Golden State Series, 1982-1987 (Box 90, Folder 15)
    - The Great Thirst revised edition, 2001-2002 (Box 90, Folder 16)
    - The Great Thirst, 1992-1995 (Box 90, Folder 17)
    - Other reviews, 1966-1987 (Box 90, Folder 18)
    - Wolper re Great Thirst, 1993 (Box 90, Folder 19)
    - Water and the West, 1975-1976 (Box 90, Folder 20)
  - Subseries 3E: Digital materials, 1994-2005
    The series includes forty-six 3.5 inch floppy disks containing manuscripts and other materials related to Hundley's research, and five CDs containing photos and other materials regarding the St. Francis Dam disaster in 1928.
    - Articles, undated (Box 94, Folder 2)
      The file includes six 3.5 inch floppy disks that contain manuscripts and articles.
    - Book chapters, undated (Box 94, Folder 3)
      The file contains seven 3.5 inch floppy disks which contain book chapters and manuscripts.
    - The Great Thirst, 1994-2000 (Box 94, Folder 4)
      The file includes fourteen 3.5 inch floppy disks containing manuscripts and revisions for The Great Thirst.
    - St. Francis Dam, undated (Box 94, Folder 5)
      The file includes five 3.5 inch floppy disks containing materials and research related to the St. Francis Dam disaster and William Mulholland.
    - St. Francis Dam images and interviews, undated (Box 91, Folder 5)
      The folder has five CDs containing images, photographs, and interviews regarding the St. Francis Dam.
    - Other materials, circa 2005 (Box 94, Folder 6)
      The file includes four 3.5 inch floppy disks containing other materials related to Hundley's work.
    - Water and the West, undated (Box 94, Folder 7)
      The file includes seven 3.5 inch floppy disks containing manuscripts and revisions for Water and the West.
    - Whitsett paper, undated (Box 94, Folder 8)
      The file includes three 3.5 inch floppy disks containing materials related to the Whitsett Seminar and Lecture series at California State University Northridge.
- Series 4: Water projects and reports, 1974-2003
  Assorted reports, periodicals, and appendixes for major water projects. Additional materials include one CD.
  Arranged by project title in fourteen subseries:
  4A. All-American Canal Lining Project.
  4B. Cadiz Groundwater Storage.
  4C. CalFed Bay-Delta Program.
  4D. California State Water Project.
  4E. California Water Plan.
  4F. Central Valley Improvement Act.
  4G. Colorado River Report.
  4H. Imperial Irrigation District.
  4I. Los Vaqueros Reservoir Enlargement.
  4J. Lower Owens River Project.
  4K. Salton Sea Restoration Project.
  4L. Shasta Dam and Reservoir.
  4M. Southern California's Integrated Water Resources Plan.
  4N. Urban Water Management Plan for the City of Los Angeles.
  - Subseries 4A: All-American Canal Lining Project, 1994
    - Cultural resource overview, 1994 January; (1 item). (Box 70, Folder 1)
      Report prepared for the Lower Colorado Regional Office Bureau of Reclamation, Boulder City, Nevada.
    - Final Environmental Impact Statement/Report (FEIS/R), (4 items). (Box 70, Folder 2-5)
      - Statement/report, (1 item). (Box 70, Folder 2)
      - Public involvement appendix, (1 item). (Box 70, Folder 3)
      - Social appendix, (1 item). (Box 70, Folder 4)
      - Geohydrology appendix, (1 item). (Box 70, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 4B: Cadiz groundwater storage, circa 1999
    - Cadiz Groundwater storage and dry-year supply program (report no.1157), circa 1999; (1 item). (Box 70, Folder 6)
      Draft environmental impact report.
  - Subseries 4C: CalFed Bay-Delta Program, 1998-1999
    - Advisory Council Meeting Package, 1998-1999; (5 items). (Box 71, Folder 1-5)
      - Package on procedures for meetings, governance, functions and authorities, 1998 October 29; (1 item). (Box 71, Folder 1)
      - Assorted materials, 1999 January 21; (1 item). (Box 71, Folder 2)
      - Recommendations on Restoration Coordination, draft long term government proposals, etc., 1999 September 16; (1 item). (Box 71, Folder 3)
      - Recommendations to the CALFED Policy Group re implementation of the CALFED Program, 1999 October 28; (1 item). (Box 71, Folder 4)
      - Focus on groundwater, storage actions, etc., 1999 December 12; (1 item). (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous, 1998-1999; (7 items). (Box 71, Folder 6)
      Meeting package, draft staging and implementation plan, meeting notices, memorandums, etc.
    - Environmental Impact Statement/Report (EIS/R), 1998 March; (15 items). (Box 71, Box 72, Box 73)
      - Full report and executive summary, (2 items). (Box 71, Folder 7)
      - EIS/R Technical Appendices, (13 items).
        - Ecosystem restoration, (1 item). (Box 71, Folder 8)
          Developing a strategic plan.
        - Ecosystem restoration, vol.1, (1 item). (Box 72, Folder 1)
        - Ecosystem restoration, vol.2, (1 item). (Box 72, Folder 2)
          - Endangered Species Act compliance., (1 item). (Box 72, Folder 3)
        - Implementation strategy, (1 item). (Box 72, Folder 4)
        - Long-term levee protection plan, (1 item). (Box 72, Folder 5)
        - No action alternative, (1 item). (Box 72, Folder 6)
        - Program goals and objectives, (1 item). (Box 72, Folder 7)
        - Project alternatives, (1 item). (Box 72, Folder 8)
        - Storage and conveyance, (1 item). (Box 72, Folder 9)
          Refinement process overview.
        - Water quality program, (1 item). (Box 72, Folder 10)
        - Water use efficiency component, (1 item). (Box 73, Folder 1)
        - Watershed management strategy, (1 item). (Box 73, Folder 2)
    - Phase II report, 1998-1999; (3 items). (Box 73, Folder 3-5)
      - Interim report, 1999 March; (1 item). (Box 73, Folder 3)
      - Revised report (folder 1 of 2), 1998 December 18; (1 item). (Box 73, Folder 4)
      - Revised report (folder 2 of 2), 1999 June; (1 item). (Box 73, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 4D: California State Water Project, 1974-1994
    - Bulletin no.200, 1974 November; (1 item). (Box 73, Folder 6)
      vol.1: History, planning, and early progress
    - Bulletin no.118-80, 1980 January; (1 item). (Box 73, Folder 7)
      Ground water basins in California: Report to the legislature in response to Water Code Section 12924.
    - Bulletin no.132-74, 1974 June; (1 item). (Box 73, Folder 8)
      The California State Water Project in 1974
    - Bulletin no.132-75, 1975 June; (1 item). (Box 73, Folder 9)
      The California State Water Project in 1974.
    - Bulletin no.132-77, 1977 November; (1 item). (Box 73, Folder 10)
      1976 activities and future management plans.
    - Bulletin no.132-78, 1978 October; (1 item). (Box 74, Folder 1)
      1977 activities and future management plans.
    - Bulletin no.132-79, 1979 November; (1 item). (Box 74, Folder 2)
      1978 activities and future management plans.
    - Bulletin no.132-80, 1980 October; (1 item). (Box 74, Folder 3)
      Current activities and future management plans.
    - Bulletin no.132-81, 1981 November; (1 item). (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - Bulletin no.132-82, 1982 November; (1 item). (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - Bulletin no.132-83, 1983 November; (1 item). (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - Bulletin no.132-87, 1987 September; (1 item). (Box 75, Folder 1)
      Management of the California State Water Project.
    - Monterey agreement, 1994 December; (1 item). (Box 75, Folder 2)
      Summary of principles.
  - Subseries 4E: California Water Plan, 1989-2000
    - Update, vol.1-2, 1998 January; (2 items). (Box 75, Folder 3-4)
      Bulletin 160-98 for public review.
      - vol.1, (1 item). (Box 75, Folder 3)
      - vol.2, (1 item). (Box 75, Folder 4)
      - DPEIS--Technical appendices (vol.1-9), 1989-2000; (9 items). (Box 76, Box 77, Box 78, Box 79)
        - vol.1, (1 item). (Box 76, Folder 4)
          Development of the no-action alternative.
          Summary of pre-CVPIA conditions.
          Evaluation of preliminary alternatives.
          Public involvement.
        - vol.2, (1 item). (Box 77, Folder 1)
          Surface water supplies and facilities operations.
          Soils and geology.
          Groundwater.
          CVP power resources.
        - vol.3, (1 item). (Box 77, Folder 2)
          Fisheries
        - vol.4, (1 item). (Box 78, Folder 1)
          Vegetations and wildlife.
          Recreation.
          Fish, wildlife and recreation economics.
        - vol.5, (1 item). (Box 78, Folder 2)
          Agricultural economics and land use.
          Water transfer opportunities; Municipal and industrial land use and demographics.
          Municipal water costs.
          Regional economics.
          Social analysis.
        - vol.6, (1 item). (Box 78, Folder 3)
          Visual resources.
          Air quality.
          Cultural resources.
          Delta as a source of drinking water.
        - vol.7, (1 item). (Box 79, Folder 1)
          PROSIM M/M.
          SANJASM M/M.
          CVGSM M/M/.
        - vol.8, (1 item). (Box 79, Folder 2)
          CVPM M/M.
          CVPTM M/M.
          Municipal water costs M/M.
          IMPLAN M/M.
        - vol.9, 1989-2000; (1 item). (Box 79, Folder 3)
          Fish habitat water quality M/M.
          Vegetation and wildlife M/M.
          Recreation M/M.
          Fish wildlife and recreation economics M/M.
          - Subseries 4G: Colorado River Report, 1989-2000
            - Executive Director's Monthly Report, 1989 October 10 - 2000 June; (4 folders). (Box 79, Box 80)
              - ., 1989 October 10 - 1991 July 9; (21 items). (Box 79, Folder 4)
              - ., 1994 July 14 - 1995 December 5; (14 items). (Box 79, Folder 5)
              - ., 1996 February 14 - 1997 December 16; (23 items). (Box 80, Folder 1)
              - ., 1998 January 13 - 2000 June 13; (28 items). (Box 80, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 4F: Central Valley Improvement Act, 1997-1999
    - Draft Programmatic Environmental Impact Statement (DPEIS), 1997 September - 1999 June; (12 items). (Box 76, Box 77, Box 78, Box 79)
      - Statement (DPEIS), 1997 September; (1 item). (Box 76, Folder 1)
      - Executive summary, 1997 September; (1 item). (Box 76, Folder 2)
      - Supplement, 1999 June; (1 item). (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 4H: Imperial Irrigation District (IID), 1988-2003
    This subseries contains one CD.
    - Assessment, 1997 June; (1 item). (Box 80, Folder 3)
      1987-1996 assessment of IID water use prepared for the U.S. Bureau of Reclamation.
    - Quantification Settlement Agreement cases, circa 2003 (Box 92, Folder 1-7)
      These folders include one CD, reports, correspondence, legal amendments, statements, and other documents related to water transfer agreements between the San Diego Water Authority, Imperial Irrigation District, and several other state agencies.
    - Water conservation agreements, 1988-1998; (8 items). (Box 80, Folder 4-6)
      - Agreement for transfer of conserved water by and between IID and San Diego County Water Authority, 1998 January-April; (6 items). (Box 80, Folder 4)
        Includes related documents and a county economic impact analysis.
      - Water conservation agreement between the MWD of Southern California and IID, 1989 December; (1 item). (Box 80, Folder 5)
      - Agreement for the implementation of a water conservation program and use of conserved water, 1988 December 22; (1 item). (Box 80, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 4I: Los Vaqueros Reservoir Enlargement, 1997
    - Enlargement plan, 1997 October; (1 item). (Box 80, Folder 7)
      Facility descriptions and updated cost estimates.
  - Subseries 4J: Lower Owens River Project, 1997
    - Ecosystem management plan, 1997; (7 items). (Box 80, Folder 8)
      Action plan and concept documents, appendixes, memorandums, etc.
  - Subseries 4K: Salton Sea Restoration Project, 2000
    - Environmental impact statement/report, 2000 January-February; (1 item). (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - Figures to accompany the report, 2000 January-February; (2 items). (Box 81, Folder 2)
      Related figures and a letter to Norris Hundley from the Salton Sea Authority.
  - Subseries 4L: Shasta Dam and Reservoir, 1997-1998
    - Shasta Lake enlargement, 1997-1998; (2 items). (Box 81, Folder 3)
      Facility descriptions and updated cost estimates for Shasta Lake enlargement.
      Appraisal assessment of the potential for enlarging Shasta Dam and Reservoir.
  - Subseries 4M: Southern California's Integrated Water Resources Plan, 1996
    - "Executive summary", 1996 March; (2 items). (Box 81, Folder 4)
    - vol.1: "The long-term resources plan", 1996 March; (1 item). (Box 81, Folder 5)
    - vol.2: "Metropolitan's system overview", 1996 March; (1 item). (Box 81, Folder 6)
    - vol.3: "Technical appendices", 1996 January; (1 item). (Box 81, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 4N: Urban Water Management Plan for the City of Los Angeles, 1995
    - Executive summary and overview, 1995 November; (1 item). (Box 81, Folder 8)
- Series 5: Other activities, 1965-2007
  The series contains correspondence, petitions, reports, notes, conference papers, and a card index related to Hundley's activities as a professor at UCLA. Additional materials include one photograph of John Caughey.
  - Angela Davis case, 1969 (Box 95, Folder 1)
  - Advisory Committee on Indian Treaties Project, 1970-1972 (Box 95, Folder 2)
  - Caughey: Correspondence, 1969-1994 (Box 95, Folder 3)
  - Caughey: John and Laree Caughey Foundation, 1982-2001 (Box 95, Folder 4)
  - Caughey: Memorial, 1982-1996 (Box 95, Folder 5)
  - Caughey: Papers, stories, and much more, 1967-1981; 1967-1968 (Box 95, Folder 6)
  - Children's documentary: Colorado River War of the 1930s, 2006 (Box 95, Folder 7)
  - Conference: Reagan conference University of California Santa Barbara, 2001-2002 (Box 95, Folder 8)
  - Conference: UCLA conference re Norris Hundley, Jr., 2000 (Box 95, Folder 9)
  - Henry J. Bruman funds, bequest, research and trust, 1992-2005 (Box 96, Folder 1-2, Box 95, Folder 10)
  - Interview summary, undated (Box 96, Folder 3)
  - John Schutz, 2002-2006 (Box 96, Folder 4)
  - Library subcomittee (college library), 1972 (Box 96, Folder 5)
  - Lectures: global warming and climate change, 2007 (Box 96, Folder 6)
  - Lectures: water talk, 1992 November 29 (Box 96, Folder 7)
  - Lectures: Whitsett, 1998-2000 (Box 96, Folder 8)
  - March on Montgomery, 1965 (Box 96, Folder 9)
  - Moving Water project, 1999-2001 (Box 96, Folder 10)
  - Notes: Environmental history, circa 1994 (Box 96, Folder 11)
  - Notes: Gary Weatherford, circa 1994 (Box 96, Folder 12)
  - Notes: Parker Dam, 2004 (Box 96, Folder 13)
  - Ted Saloutos funeral, 1980 (Box 96, Folder 14)
  - UCLA strike, 1970 (Box 96, Folder 15)
  - Journal referees index: A-L, 1974-1996 (Box 97)
  - Journal referees index: M-XYZ, 1974-1996 (Box 98)